David Shar

Process Engineer Assistant

Philadelphia, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/David-Shar/57635cc23f80f64c

Motivated professional experienced in production and petroleum engineering within the oil and gas industry. Develop plans for the

completion of wells, testing and construction sites. Interpret and process data and supervise crews in preparation and equipment

calibration. Maintain knowledge and skills in management/leadership, communications, and organizational operations and project

management.

- Superb analytical and problem solving skills
 Adept at developing requirements and processing
- Innovative and independent-minded priority tasks
- · Highly adaptive to different cultures and customs · Accustomed to managing team members and
- Demonstrated ability to coordinate and collaborate effectively carrying out tasks in a team environment with peers to accomplish objectives

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

WORK EXPERIENCE

Process Engineer Assistant

Al-Rushaid Group - 2013 to 2013

Designed gas and petrochemical plants and provided onsite monitoring during the construction progress. Designed tanks,

reactors, and heat exchangers using Aspen HYSYS and SuperPro. Ensured project timeline was maintained and all equipment

installed correctly.

Process Engineer Assistant, Arabian Consulting Engineering Center; Alkobar City 2012

• Performed pipe stress analysis, various engineering calculations and field verifications. Primary focus was to prevent the corrosion

caused by the high percentage of sulfur in oil and gas. Performed pipe stress analysis, engineering calculations and field

verifications.

Process Engineer Assistant, Baker Oil Tools

Dhahran City - 2011 to 2011

Designed Compressors and pumps with a focus area to design a combined system that take the gas compresses it and sends it to the pumps to meet the requirement for flow rate in pipes.

Process Engineer Assistant, Frank's Rawabi

Alkobar City - 2010 to 2010

Designed Heat Exchangers (shell and tube with consideration to the type of materials to go in the shell and tube sides and the flow

rates.

• Analyzed and calculated capacity of energy that can be extracted per hour and how to maximize it with lowering the cost of the equipment.

Process Engineer Assistant

Alkobar City - 2009 to 2009

Drilled oil and gas wells and ensured equipment on rig was in proper working condition.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Chemical Engineering

University of Colorado - Boulder, CO 2014

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

KEY PROFICIENCIES

- Fluent in English and Arabic Well Planning and Control Proficient in computer
- Petroleum Production Reservoir Engineering and programs including: Aspen Engineering Fluid Flow HYSYS, SuperPro Designer,
- Natural Gas Engineering PetroPhysics &Formation Datasheets, Matlab, Polymath,
- Improved Petroleum Recovery Evaluation MathCAD, Visio, Microsoft Process Site Assessment & Excel, Access, Word, and
- Risk Analysis and Property Remediation PowerPoint Evaluation